## Jeffrey A. Dill

## github.com/jeffdill2

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Programmer with 6+ years of experience matching unique solutions to unique problems. My strength and passion is being presented with new business needs and solving them with the tools available. I've had the privilege of being presented with different tools at each employer, giving me exposure to a broad spectrum of different languages, IDE's, SDK's, API's, and software suites – and I am always actively seeking more exposure to new technologies.

### **EMPLOYMENT**

### August 2012 – Present Heeter

## Programmer Pittsburgh, PA

- Developed the entire back-end and helped to develop the front-end for Heeter's web-to-print / print-on-demand solution, ShopPRO. This solution includes a client-facing web portal using JavaScript for UI customization and AJAX for data calls, a SQL Server backend, two C# applications, and an ASP.NET (Web Forms) credit card payment website.
- Responsible for maintaining the data, code, and communications that drive a high-profile fulfillment project for a large healthcare client – this project being the largest source of revenue for the company.
- Helped build and now maintain the company website Heeter.com using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL Server, and DotNetNuke as a CMS.

### June 2010 – August 2012 Classic Graphics

# Programmer Charlotte, NC

- When a large client's campaign requirements changed drastically, forcing us to use an outside vendor for a portion of their data work, I wrote an application in Visual FoxPro to manage the relationship between our internal software and the outside vendor's software. Between the application and the implementation of new standards/procedures, automated jobs that were expected to be quick-turnaround were able to remain as such. All of this was accomplished weeks ahead of the client's requested implementation time-frame.
- Co-lead an initiative to create a new Job Order Entry system. I created a highly-dynamic Excel document, built on top of 7,900 lines of VBA. Previously, a job required five different forms to move through the building – it now takes one efficient, standardized, easy-to-understand document that utilizes several IT concepts such as Principle of Least Privilege.
- Wrote two separate applications in Visual FoxPro, and utilizing Pervasive PSQL, to meet the extremely quick turnaround demands of a high-revenue project. The first application built an intricate data report in Excel that encompassed multiple points along the data-processing timeline for their jobs. The other populated the above mentioned Job Order Entry form, preparing it for the Production department. Due to the size and complexity of the project, for either process to be accomplished manually required between 2 and 4 hours. Both applications accomplished the previously manual tasks in about 30 seconds, eliminated the potential for human error, and enabled us to meet the client's demanding schedule.

### June 2007 – June 2010 SourceLink Carolina

# Programmer Greenville, SC

- Primarily created (designed, coded, tested, debugged, documented, implemented, and maintained) in-house data-centric
   GUI and console applications geared towards direct marketing campaigns and any associated backend tracking/reporting.
- Secondarily created applications for the Data Processing team that increased the efficiency and quality control of
  processes that would otherwise have had to be done manually. Also, created class libraries for the Programming Team
  that made full use of object-oriented concepts for the sake of coding efficiency and standardization.
- Made use of COM technology to interface between Visual FoxPro and Microsoft Office, primarily for dynamic generation of spreadsheets for the purposes of reporting, as well as reading data from client-created spreadsheets to dynamically drive how an application functions.
- Helped to transition several million dollars worth of work, over a 3 month period, from the Chicago division to the Greenville division to reduce organizational expenses.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Greenville Technical College**

Individual classes taken for self-study purposes: Visual Basic .NET, Relational Databases; 2009-2010

### **Clemson University**

Bachelor of Arts degree in Sociology, minor in Philosophy; May 2007.

#### COMPETENCIES

### Software:

Visual Studio 2008-2012, SQL Server 2005-2012, Xcode, GitHub, Android Studio, Microsoft Office

### Languages/Technologies:

C#, ASP.NET, Visual FoxPro 6-9, VBA, VB.NET, VB6, T-SQL, PostgreSQL, Objective-C, ANSI C, Python, JavaScript, SOAP/Web Services, XML, COM, FTP, PGP/GPG, HTML, CSS, Ruby on Rails, Git

### **Operating Systems:**

Microsoft Windows XP / 2008 Server / 7, Mac OS X, Linux Ubuntu, iOS, Android

244 Castle Shannon Blvd

Pittsburgh, PA 15228

864.430.1614

jeffdill2@gmail.com